<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quick Byte</title>
    <link>https://isaiahp.xyz/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Quick Byte</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 15:16:03 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://isaiahp.xyz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What the heck is bitcoin</title>
      <link>https://isaiahp.xyz/posts/bitcoin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 15:16:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaiahp.xyz/posts/bitcoin/</guid>
      <description>This is a very simplified introduction to understanding what bitcoin is, bitcoin itself is not one thing, it can be divided into 3 parts
 Bitcoin as currency payment network system blockchain underlying technology  P2P payment system  I think that the Internet is going to be one of the major forces for reducing the role of government. The one thing that&amp;rsquo;s missing, but that will soon be developed, is a reliable e-cash - a method whereby on the Internet you can transfer funds from A to B without A knowing B or B knowing A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://isaiahp.xyz/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 14:34:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaiahp.xyz/about/</guid>
      <description>I am an independent software engineer based in London, UK. I mostly work on financial trading systems, previously I worked a ThoughtWorks. I was a grad at University of York and I was an undergrad at the University of Sydney. I have skills in a broad range of programming languages and paradigms (which includes Java, Python, C# and F#) prefer to use the best tool for the job
Contact Isaiah  PGP Key Contact details  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethink logging</title>
      <link>https://isaiahp.xyz/posts/rethink-logging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 17:00:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaiahp.xyz/posts/rethink-logging/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR  Logging is a feature of a system Primary consumer of logs are machines Use events in logs to verify a running system There are benefits to using Binary encoding  Logging can be an effective way of gathering data from a system and observing its runtime behaviour. In my experience most of application logging is ad-hoc text, which greatly diminishes the potential value of logging. Most systems tend to start off with very little logging or no logging, as the system grows and problems arise developers add additional logging, which leads to megabytes/gigabytes of similar looking text, what make things worse it often not clear what information should be logged, developers often log debug/trace level diagnostic information in development but turned off in production, which makes it very difficult to extract meaningful information to troubleshoot a problem in production, as it may be missing crucial information.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>